rtl-sdr.com 2019-05-17

# Privacy Policy

**Store**

The personal data we collect on our store at checkout is used only for the purposes of shipping out your product, and for internal accounting purposes.

**Email List**

If you sign up to our MailChimp mailing list your email will be used to send out weekly post summary emails, and information about new products.

**Comments  
**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

**Media**

If you upload images to the website or forums, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

**How long we retain your data**

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

**What rights you have over your data**

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

**Advertising**

We also use your data for advertising purposes.

We use third-party advertising companies who serve ads to help keep content free. For these partners, we put additional restrictions on how your data can be used to prevent it from misuse. For instance, we do not allow these partners to take your information for profiling and personalizing ads on other sites.

Please review the following for a full list of partners and purposes:

**Disclosure**

Your address details will be provided only to our professional shipping partners at sendfromchina.com or Amazon.com for order fulfillment. Payment processors such as PayPal may collect your data too.

We will not share your data with any other third parties unless we received authorization to do so.

**Consent**

By consenting to this privacy policy you are giving us permission to process your personal data specifically for the purposes identified.

**How We Use Cookies**

Our web site uses a technology known as cookies to store small amounts of data on our visitors’ computers or devices. Cookies are small pieces of text data that can be placed on a visitor’s computer, normally to provide enhanced functionality and/or improved relevancy of information.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select "Remember Me", your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

Cookie Name | Purpose | Example Content | Expires  
---|---|---|---  
_gat | 

This cookie does not store any user information; it's just used to limit the number of requests that have to be made to doubleclick.net.

| 1 | 10 minutes  
advanced_ads_page_impressions | 

Used to count the number of page impressions for ad display purposes.

| 1 |  10 years  
__cfduid | 

The __cfduid cookie is used to identify individual clients behind a shared IP address and apply security settings on a per-client basis. For example, if the visitor is in a coffee shop where there are a bunch of infected machines, but the specific visitor's machine is trusted (e.g. because they've completed a challenge within your Challenge Passage period), the cookie allows us to identify that client and not challenge them again. It does not correspond to any user ID in your web application, and does not store any personally identifiable information.

| dc675ee56667d7cdb38fb0...  |  30 minutes  
_ga | 

Allows Google Analytics to determine a unique user.

| GA1.2.2024253856.15272...  | 2 years  
advanced_ads_browser_width  | 

Determines the browser width

| 1450 | On closure  
_gid | 

Used by Google Analytics to distinguish users.

| GA1.2.744632804.152724...   
| 24 hours  
PHPSESSID | Used by PHP to keep track of a session. |  bt48hhdi753rp1t3d7ung8...  |  On closure
